Oh
you
from Musa Kusa and we're live on YouTube
welcome everybody to our second anti-spy
bill event I think in a few moments we
will be simulcasting on Facebook so
hello to New Zealand and hello to the
world tonight we have with us again the
awesome Kim calm and we also have with
us CIA whistleblower John Kiriakou but
before we hear from those guys we're
just going to catch up a little bit on
what's happened since the last to be and
what we'll be doing going forward so the
last event was a massive success which I
am personally really pleased about we
had put out three press releases to New
Zealand media they chose not to cover
the event but despite that within a
couple of hours of it we had achieved
3.3 million Twitter impressions we had
reached half a million people on
Facebook and we had about 10,000 live
viewers which is really incredible for
an event that was just purely spread by
word of mouth
we had no marketing budget no
corporations or governments behind us
and we did it ourselves together so
congratulations to everyone for that
after that amazing turnout our press
releases have now been picked up by New
Zealand media on Friday two days ago
news hub which is a major New Zealand
media outlet published an article about
our event tonight and it got over 2,000
shares in under 24 hours since then the
Daily Dot has also picked it up and
published two there two and a half
million Facebook followers and we are
now live also on the daily blog go to NZ
which is one of the biggest and most
significant political blog sites in New
Zealand so at the last event I told you
that we were going to hear from
activists from all of the Firewise
countries
we got through Australia and the United
States and the UK and New Zealand that
we miss Canada because of some technical
issues so tonight we're going to start
out by hearing from Bailey LeMond so as
president of the pirate party and Canada
she sent us a video message about how
the same types of legislation that we've
been subjected to in New Zealand have
also been inflicted upon the Canadian
public so Joe our awesome tech manager
is going to go ahead and play her
message for you now
hi everyone my name is Bailey LeMond I'm
an activist I'm the president of The
Pirate Party of Canada and I'm also the
vice chairwoman of pirate parties
international so I live in Canada and
Canada is part of the five eyes alliance
our situation up here so up until 1984
the Royal Canadian Mounted Police also
known as the RCMP acted as not only a
police service but as an intelligence
agency that had the power to both spy on
people and enforce the law long story
short this is very very bad they did
terrible things and in 1984 the McDonald
Commission was launched this was an
investigation into the crimes of the
RCMP which resulted in the creation of
CSIS or the Canadian security and
intelligence service which is Canada's
main spy agency to this day fast-forward
to 2015 the anti-terrorism Act also
known as bill c-51 became law under
Prime Minister Stephen Harper's
Conservative government this law is
still in place c-51 it was widely
opposed across the country it still is
and it's not only seen as problematic by
activists but by many of the spies
themselves and former spies who have
come out and said how truly awful this
law is Canada's anti-terrorism act not
only gives our various police forces and
spy agencies the power to store our
information our data and share that
information about us with one another
freely but it allows CSIS which is not a
law enforcement agency to preemptively
detain people who haven't even committed
any crimes but are seen as threats to
national security based on reasonable
suspicion so things like what you say
online if you're spreading terrorist
propaganda whatever that is right the
thing is this law doesn't even define
what any of these things really mean
leaving it open for anyone to be
targeted and locked up for their speech
for other ideas and that's just
completely onyx
I think we all agree on that but so now
today we do have a new government in
power the Liberal Party
unfortunately they fully supported bill
c-51 from the beginning however they
have promised to reform it's right now
that's what they're supposedly working
on however none of the proposed reforms
seem to address the most problematic
elements of this law that I just
described to you on Parliament's note
for the summer so it's going to be a few
weeks before they get back to it
so we'll see what happens but right now
it still stands um I think we can all
agree the state surveillance is
completely incompatible with democracy
and that free speech does not exist in a
country where the spies and the law
enforce and the law enforcement people
are given enough power to literally take
anything you say as a threat to national
security which is what we have here in
Canada and from why I understand it's
what the other five eyes countries have
- it's important to keep in mind that
surveillance is first and foremost an
issue of power where the powerful get to
invade our privacy to uphold their power
through their political system and
criminalize anyone who speaks out or
fights back this is why events like this
where the public gets to join together
to create policies that favor privacy
for the average citizen and transparency
for the state are so crucial as all of
us move forward in our respective
countries so big thank you to Susie and
the internet party for this amazing
initiative
thank you so much for that Bailey that's
really awesome it's been great to hear
from activists in each of the five
countries so my big piece of news is
that we've decided that we are going to
continue these events ongoing so we're
going because we're in election season
and we only have about six weeks to go
five six weeks ago we are actually going
to hold these events every Sunday night
for the foreseeable future to continue
to work on the draft copy of the
anti-spy bill together with all of you
and then we have been discussing an
action plan for the next 12 or so months
beyond that I'll tell you a bit more
about that later on in the program but
for now I want to move ahead and have us
hear from John so just quickly going to
read you a little thing I wrote about
John today in an op-ed for the daily
blog CIA torch of whistleblower John
Kiriakou was recruited from the high
school that he taught jared leto at in
the decades to follow he traveled the
world recruited other spies intern and
oversaw operations that captured
al-qaeda militants and sent them to
Guantanamo Bay
eventually ah trains to keep secrets
there was one he could not live with his
government was torturing people
eventually he shared what he knew with
his fellow countrymen but tonight he
will share it with New Zealand and the
world so John please take it away tell
us your story give us all the messages
that you have to give thank you so much
for having me for doing this for giving
me the opportunity the soapbox I'm happy
to do it
and I'll apologize for the lighting it's
a I have every light on in my in my room
and it's still a if you're not light
enough
anyway um you're right I was I was
recruited into the CIA when I was in
graduate school I was teaching high
school at the time at a private school
in Washington DC and as it turned out my
graduate school adviser was a CIA
officer undercover as a graduate school
adviser and he was the one who recruited
me into the agency I had never really
considered the CIA but I was getting
ready to graduate and I didn't have a
job I was getting married soon after
graduation I really needed the work
and the idea of seeing the world was
exciting to me and so I said sure I'll
go through the process so I did I went
through the process
God hired started on the first of
January 1990 and started working as an
analyst so really I was sitting in a
cubicle thinking the big thoughts
writing writing papers for the president
the vice-president the secretaries of
state and defense the national security
adviser and that was great it was a lot
of fun for a while and then I got bored
went overseas also as an analyst to the
Middle East learned to speak Arabic and
then went back to headquarters again in
1997 again I was bored and so into not
not 2000 in 1998 I made a very unusual
switch from analysis to counterterrorism
operations and and went overseas as a as
an Operations Officer like actually
trying to infiltrate terrorist groups
and either disrupt future attacks or
break up the group and found that I had
a knack for it it was dangerous
certainly but it was interesting it was
fun it was important and so I decided
well maybe I found my my place my niche
I went back to
headquarters after serving overseas in
2000 and and then September 11th hit in
2001 that changed everything at the CIA
as it turned out the CIA after 2001
returned to its roots the CIA that I had
come of age in was not the real CIA the
real CIA was one that that requires
great oversight and one that that is
constantly pushing the bounds of morals
and ethics and legality but I was as
angry as every other American on
September 11th and I volunteered
certainly to go to Afghanistan and fight
or do whatever was necessary what I
ended up doing was I was sent to
Pakistan as the chief of CIA
counterterrorism operations there and it
was in that job that in early 2002 I led
a series of raids that resulted in the
capture of Abu Zubaydah whom the CIA
believed at the time was the number
three in al-qaeda and many dozens I'm
not allowed to say the exact number but
many dozens of al-qaeda fighters at and
safe houses all over Pakistan well I had
occasion after capturing up as a beta to
have a long conversation with him in
fact I am i sat with him for 54
consecutive hours after his capture he
was very upset as you could imagine he
cried a lot he said that he would never
know the touch of a woman he would never
know the joy of fatherhood and I said
listen you are not the victim here there
were 50,000 people in those towers what
did you think we were going to do did
you think we weren't going to try to
find you to capture you or to find her
or kill bin Laden and he said that he
never wanted to attack the United States
on September 11th he wanted to attack
Israel he said all he ever wanted to do
was to kill Jews
and I said listen I am the nicest guy
that you're going to meet in this
experience my colleagues are not as nice
as I am so if there's one thing that you
do it's that you should cooperate and he
said you seem like a nice man but you're
the enemy
and I'll never cooperate I said suit
yourself later that night
CIA private jet flew in three FBI agents
and I loaded him onto the plane he asked
me to hold his hand the whole time and I
wished him the best of luck and I never
saw him again well two months later I
returned to CIA headquarters and on the
strength of the Abu Zubaydah capture I
had been promoted and I was named the
executive assistant to the CIA's deputy
director for operations and it was in
that capacity that I had access to
literally everything in the CIA every
operation every sensitive compartment
everything and it was in that position
that I realized that we had initiated
this torture program now I I was in the
cafeteria one day and a former colleague
from the CIA's Counterterrorism Center
approached me and said hey I'm glad I
ran into you
do you have any interest in being and
these were his words certified in the
use of enhanced interrogation techniques
I had never heard the term before so I
asked him what it meant and he said very
excitedly we're gonna start getting
rough with these guys and I said well
what does that mean and then he
delineated these ten torture techniques
and I said well that sounds like a
torture program I said I think I have a
moral problem with that and I declined
well as it turned out of the 14 people
that they approached asking if they
wanted to be trained in these torture
techniques I was the only one who said
no that was a source of great
disappointment for me
I kept my mouth shut I left the CIA two
years later and still kept my mouth shut
but then in late 2007 I couldn't live
with the administration's lies anymore
it seemed like every time I turned on
the television President Bush was
denying that there was a torture program
and the CIA's director at the time and
and directors after him George Tenet
were all denying that there was a
torture program and I knew that that was
a lie I knew that they were lying to the
American people and I believe in
transparency I believe that the American
people have a right to know what their
country is doing in their name and so I
decided in December of 2007 that I was
going to blow the whistle on this
program and I gave a nationally
televised interview to ABC News in which
I did exactly that I said three things
three things that have utterly changed
the course of the rest of my life I said
that the CIA was torturing its prisoners
I said that torture was official US
government policy it was not the result
of a rogue as President Bush had said
and I said that the torture program had
been personally approved by the
President himself as you can imagine
within 24 hours the FBI began
investigating me and this is where the
story in my view becomes very sad it
becomes unamerican the FBI investigated
me for a full year from December 2007 to
December 2008 and they decided at the
end of that investigation that I had not
committed a crime that the interview was
not a crime because the information was
not inherently classified and so they
closed the investigation four weeks
later Barack Obama was inaugurated as
president of the United States Barack
Obama the self-described most
transparent president in history and I
should preface this by saying that I
believed in the whole hope and change
slogan of the Obama campaign not just
that I worked on the Obama campaign I
took my children to the inauguration so
they could see this historic moment when
when for the first time in history an
african-american man had become
president I mean this was an incredible
moment for America but what I did not
know was that as soon as he became
president the CIA asked Barack Obama to
secretly reopen the case against me
which he did
I had no idea that I was under
investigation I had no idea that the FBI
was intercepting my phone calls and was
reading my emails and had teams of
surveillance on me and so I went about
my regular business so what was my
regular business well believe it or not
john kerry who at the time was the
chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations
Committee called me and invited me to
join the Senate Foreign Relations
Committee staff as the chief
investigator investigating waste fraud
abuse and illegality in the State
Department and so I took that job again
having no idea that I was under FBI
investigation for what became five
felony charges the FBI investigated me
for three more years and finally in
January of 2012 I was charged with these
five felonies including three counts of
espionage espionage is one of the
gravest crimes with which an American
can be charged and frequently it carries
with it the death penalty for telling
the American people that the CIA was
torturing its prisoners now there's
something that happened in the interim
and I had no idea the significance of it
until this whole thing was over one of
the great things the most wonderful
things about working for the Senate
Foreign Relations Committee is that you
get to have lunch with foreign diplomats
all the time and you know you get
together for lunch you talk about the
events of the day whatever happens to be
in the paper you talk about diplomacy I
got a call one day a totally normal and
routine call from a Japanese diplomat it
was the number three in the Japanese
embassy in Washington and he invited me
to lunch
so we went to a small restaurant on
Capitol Hill and I remember the lunch as
being delightful I remember we talked
about Israeli elections and Turkish
elections and the arab-israeli peace
process and at the end of the lunch he
said to me so what's next for you and I
said well I'm actually thinking of
resigning from the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee I promised Senator
Kerry that I would give him two years
it's been two and a half and I think I'd
like to go into business for myself I
have five kids I need to start saving
some money for college
I think I'm I'd like to go into the
private sector and very excitedly he
said no don't do that if you give me
information I can give you money and I
said what's wrong with you do you have
any idea how many times I've made that
pitch in my career shame on you
I told him I ended the lunch and I went
directly to the office of the Senate
security officer and I said I was just
pitched by a foreign intelligence
officer and he said oh is it that damn
Russian again and I said no no it's it's
a Japanese of all things and he said
really a Japanese okay
he said well sometimes they like to see
what we're doing
visa vie trade and then he asked me to
write it up as a memo he was going to
send it to the FBI I said fine so I sat
there in his office and I wrote up the
memo he sent it to the FBI and then
called me in the next day and said two
FBI agents were going to come and
interview me so they finally came up
came to my office and said okay here's
what we want you to do we want you to
call him back and we want you to try to
get him to tell you exactly what
information he wants and how much money
he's willing to pay for it I said okay
do you want me to wear a wire or
something and they said no we're gonna
be at the next table and we'll just
listen to the conversation I said fine
so the morning of that lunch they called
me and said that something had come up I
should just go forward with the lunch
and write them another memo so I met
with this guy a second time and then
they asked me to meet with him a third
time and a fourth time and a fifth time
which I did because I'm a patriot
well I wrote up these memos after each
lunch and finally in the fifth lunch he
said that he had been promoted he had
been transferred to his dream job and he
was going to be the number two in the
Japanese embassy in Cairo a year after
that last lunch I was arrested and we
received discovery from the Justice
Department now discovery is when the
prosecution has to turn over to the
defense literally everything that it's
collected so that the defense can use
that to defend itself in this discovery
we found a series of memos the first
indicated that there never was any
Japanese diplomat he was an FBI agent
undercover and he was trying to get me
to commit real espionage and I asked my
lead attorney why would they do such a
thing
and he said because they have a
case and they know it's a case I
hadn't committed espionage I had blown
the whistle fair and square I told the
American people what they had a right to
know well we also received three memos
between the CIA and the Justice
Department the CIA wrote to the Justice
Department and said charge him with
espionage the Justice Department wrote
back and said but he hasn't committed
espionage and the CIA wrote back and
said charge him anyway and make him
defend himself and that was the Obama
administration now the Espionage Act
here in the United States was written in
1917 to combat German saboteurs during
the first world war between 1917 and
2009 it was used to charge three
Americans with espionage for talking to
the press just under the Obama
administration eight Americans were
charged with espionage for speaking to
the press the Obama administration used
the Espionage Act as an iron fist to
stamp out dissent
now I was a guy who always colored
within the lines I was nobody special
you know there was nothing unusual about
me in any way I'm just a guy I'm just a
normal guy but one of the things that so
grossly disappointed me was that I was
the only one who said something you know
there were hundreds of people inside the
CIA who knew about this torture program
hundreds we now know from the Senate
torture report that people inside were
objecting to it they were writing cables
back from the secret prison saying this
is awful this is disgusting a couple of
them curtailed their assignments which
means they asked to return to
headquarters it's a career-ending move
but not a single one of them said
something publicly even worse than that
not a single one of them ever said
anything to the Senate or House
Intelligence Committee the oversight
committees I was the only one who did
that was a source of great
disappointment for me well in the end
Kim and I were talking about this off
camera a few minutes ago
in the end I had to defend myself
against these five felony charges I was
facing 45 years in prison and over the
course of 10 months our negotiations had
brought the Justice Department down to
10 years they wanted me to do 10 years
in a federal penitentiary this was what
they called their best and final offer
and I turned it down and I said two
things I said first of all I haven't
done anything wrong and because I
haven't done anything wrong I'm not
doing ten minutes let alone ten years in
prison secondly I'm a very longtime
former CIA officer and in my 15 years in
the CIA
I witnessed hideous crimes against
humanity war crimes and I'm going to
have to testify in my own defense and I
might accidentally say something about
these horrible crimes that I've
witnessed my colleagues perpetrate over
the years and it might slip out in the
course of my my testimony
and so the CIA came back and said all
right do two and a half years you'll end
up serving under two I actually turned
that down and then one of my eleven
attorneys the one who I liked and
respected the most pulled me aside and
said you just don't get it
this isn't about innocence or guilt this
is about cutting your losses this is
about inflicting the least amount of
pain on yourself and your family it
doesn't matter whether you did it or
didn't do it the federal government wins
ninety eight point two percent of its
cases according to ProPublica and he
said if you were my brother I would beg
you to take this deal so I'm begging you
take the deal he said this can be a blip
in your life or it can be the defining
event of your life you can be home early
enough that your children won't even
remember you were gone or you can get
out when your children are in college
and so I took the deal it becomes an
economic decision with that said I would
do the whole damn thing over again
somebody had to say something
transparency is real it's important a
democracy can't function without
transparency and again the American
people have a right to know what their
government is doing in their name and so
I'm glad that I said something I'm glad
that I said something I'm glad that I
have continued to say something it's
cost me my marriage my wife left three
months ago she said it's just too much
work to be mrs. John Kiriakou to tell
you the truth I don't blame her
but I had to do the right thing and this
was the price that that we all have to
pay it was all worth it
thanks for listening
John this is an incredible story a
remarkable story
so really the FBI were involved in an
attempt to entrap you is that what you
were just telling us there yeah it's
it's all about entrapment to tell you
the truth and that's why when I got to
prison I've been in prison let's see
March April May Jim for months when Ed
Snowden went public with his revelations
and I wrote an open letter to ed Snowden
I followed it up with a private letter
through we have a mutual attorney but I
I told him what I thought he should do
just from the benefit of my own
experience I told him to find the best
national security attorney's money could
buy essentially my attorneys which he
did he engaged my attorneys I told him
to cultivate his natural bases of
support especially on Capitol Hill now
that's taking a little bit of time but
he's done that as well and it's funny
because the far left and the far right
end up meeting at a point the the
ideological spectrum I believe is not a
straight line it's a circle and and
they've come together at the point where
they really care about civil liberties
and it's those civil libertarians on the
left and the right who have come out in
support of Ed Snowden because of that we
are finally just now beginning to see
elements of the Patriot Act fall by the
wayside finally after 16 years I think
that's thanks to Ed Snowden
and the third thing I said and this was
the most important thing don't ever ever
under any circumstances talk to the FBI
I said they will lie they will cheat
they will twist your words they'll
wiretap you and then take your
statements out of context to use against
you in court remember they get promoted
if you go to prison that's the only way
for them to get ahead
in their careers is for you to go to
prison and if you go to prison for a
long period of time they're gonna get a
performance bonus they're going to get
transferred to a better position inside
the FBI I mean it's ridiculous it's like
everything a democracy should not be so
I got a visit from it from Ed's father
he actually came to prison to visit me
and told me that Edie had appreciated
the letter that he had taken it
seriously and that um and he was abiding
by it that meant a lot to me all worth
it was huge it's extremely important for
people who are going through this to
have people who have been through it
before
able to do so that was an amazing
initiative that you took up to on that
point I got very lucky actually before I
left for prison there were something
like 625 people who had expressed
interest in being placed on a mailing
list an email mailing list just to
receive something from me saying I'm
fine I'm in prison it's not so bad I'm
gonna be okay so I wrote this open
letter and I sent it to my attorney she
sent it to the publisher of
firedoglake.com which no longer exists
that was jane hampshire and jane I had
no idea Jane was friendly with Arianna
Huffington and so my initial open letter
which I called a letter from Loreto
received a million hits thanks to
Arianna Huffington when I wrote the open
letter to Ed Snowden again I just
expected it to go essentially to my
attorney maybe to a handful a couple
hundred of other people but eventually
it would make its way back to Ed again
with Ariana's help it went viral I ended
up with over two million hits
CNN drove
the prison to interview me the the
American news program 60 minutes came to
the prison it was in everything from
like Time magazine to Playboy to The
Economist's to the Atlantic Monthly and
thanks to Arianna we got it immediately
back to Eddie
two million hits and and I got my side
of the story out there
this is something that I learned early
on is we really need to take advantage
of our access to the media I mean we can
we can have these great ideas and we can
sit and talk amongst ourselves about how
smart we are and how creative we are
we're create ideas we we have and it
doesn't make any difference if nobody
knows that we're doing it so if we have
access to the press that's how we win
you know John let me weigh in here first
of all thank you so much
what an incredible story you are a hero
for done what you did and I admire your
courage thank you so much King you know
in my case the first priority was to
make sure that I don't get bail because
they are very much aware that the moment
you are outside you can tell your side
of the story
and in my case they had told their side
of the story with the indictment and a
massive press release and they gave my
indictment and some background
information to about a dozen news
outlets who were ready to press print
the moment the rate went down on my on
my home and on my family so for me to be
able to get bail and to get out and talk
about what happened was their biggest
concern because they knew already you
know that what they did was at the edge
of what's possible in a novel copyright
case and then their second priority was
after I had bail to silence me by
disallowing me to have any
had access whatsoever anyone coming to
my house had to leave their smartphones
outside I had very strict bail
conditions that were restricting my
speech and limiting my ability to be out
there and tell my story and thirdly they
seized all my money to make sure that I
can't afford any lawyers because that is
the biggest power they have they have
unlimited funds they have a huge war
chest they can keep going for years and
appeal every win you have until you run
out of money you run out of patience
with your relationships who just can't
carry the burden of this fight anymore
that's why your relationship broke up
that's why my relationship broke up they
really want to destroy you and silence
you so for you to do the exact opposite
for you to go and write these letters
from prison and do all these interviews
and to keep talking about it that is
really the most powerful and courageous
thing and the more people learn about
your story the more people can hear what
happened to you they will get angry they
will feel just like I did
listening to you very upset you know not
understanding why a government could do
something like that
why a government that is supposed to
serve the people is doing something like
that to their own citizens and for that
I want to applaud you it's amazing that
you tell us a story and share it with
everyone thank you so much you know you
raised such an important point that that
I meant to to mention and the point is
that it's not just to prosecute you
you're right it's to ruin you
financially personally professionally
it's to separate you from your friends
from your family from your natural
allies or supporters
they do they do these things in the
United States there are two two
strategies that the prosecution uses in
the United States one is called charge
stacking and that is let's say you
really did do something wrong let's say
you conspired with somebody to do
something well they won't just charge
you with conspiracy they'll charge you
with five ten twenty different crimes
and they'll force you to defend yourself
against those twenty different crimes to
the point where you go bankrupt and that
usually takes you know six to twelve
months and then once you're bankrupt and
you're weak and you're desperate they'll
come back and they'll say well we'll
drop all of these charges but one if you
plead guilty to one and take this number
of years in prison well that's what they
intended in the very beginning they know
they knew you didn't commit these 20
crimes they intended for you to take the
plea and because you're broken by then
well of course you're going to take the
plea and that's why they win ninety
eight point two percent of their cases
now the other reason that you're going
to take that plea is that juries here in
the United States especially where you
and I have been charged in the Eastern
District of Virginia they would convict
a bologna sandwich of a crime if the
government asks them to you know when
your jury Kim and this is a warning to
you when your jury is made up of people
from the CIA the FBI the Homeland
Security Department the Defense
Department and the intelligence
contractor community you don't have a
prayer you can't win it doesn't matter
if you're innocent you're not going to
win you're gonna go to prison and if you
don't take a plea you're likely gonna
die in prison that's their goal their
goal is for you to die in prison not
because they don't like you necessarily
but because they want to scare the
living daylights out of everybody else
so that they
say you see what we did to cure yaku you
want that to happen to you well you
better keep your mouth shut in the mean
absolute you're absolutely right John
and what I've learned about the justice
system in the u.s. absolutely confirms
that let me give you one example the
church that is on my case in the
district court in the Eastern District
of Virginia he was a lawyer before he
started his career as a judge for Disney
it was a partner in a law firm for the
Walt Disney Corporation their largest
client and has anyone ever heard of
conflict of interest you know he is the
judge overseeing the world's largest
copyright case so that is number one the
second big surprise was how easy they
could commit judge shopping because
every judge in this district is on at a
certain date and if they make sure that
they submit their a case on that day
they know they're going to get that
judge so they picked my judge the judge
has a history to work on copyright for
the studios and on top of that I found
out through you know my research and we
hired an investigator that the judge
himself had an issue with the law
because someone burned his house down in
Virginia right and the fire department
came and the FBI came and was picking
the news and everyone was like who was
trying to hurt this judge and a big
investigation was jump-started and then
it turned out it was his own son and
they dropped the whole thing and never
did anyone hear about it again no one
was charged everything was dropped and
the judge was taken care of by his
government and this is the guy who made
a decision that said destroy all of
these servers worldwide take down his
entire business that make 220 people
unemployed go do the raid
you know how in the world can you have
a fair process with someone like that in
charge and you know everything that I've
learned over the last five and a half
years is that the entire system is
completely corrupt the 98% success rate
did you spoke about earlier those are
not cases that they win in court in
front of a jury those are all plea
bargain deals they torture you into
accepting guilt even if you've done
nothing wrong they give you this list of
20 charges in my case they want me to
throw in jail for 88 years and you're
absolutely right from everything that
I've seen from the beginning in my case
all they care about is hurting me and
killing me they want to lock me up for
as long as possible and you are
absolutely right you know if I die they
would probably celebrate that you know
and the thing is every now and then they
run into people like us you know smart
people who understand what's going on
who understand that there are other
people out there who are interested in
this who are fighting against this
injustice who want to reform a system
that is designed to be unjust and you
know our service to the public really is
to fight these cases to the end to let
everyone know on and on again about
what's going on remind everyone because
that is the only way we're going to
change anything about this if you and I
and Julian and all the other people that
are being persecuted especially by this
prosecution team in the Eastern District
of Virginia the deep state persecutors
they always remind me of the church's
Inquisition you know if we don't do this
no one else will and you know we need to
make sure that through the events like
this we let people know about it and
your story is just a prime example
because what you have done you have
exposed a crime
it is a crime in the United States to
torture someone right yes it's not and
what do they do to circumvent US law
they ship them off to foreign prison
secret locations where they torture them
and then they say well the US law really
doesn't apply but then in my copyright
case they say just because I have a few
servers in the United States and I've
never been there
my business wasn't based there I didn't
sign up to their laws yet Here I am I
can be extradited so how does it work
that these guys can torture anyone they
want in these foreign sites by American
spies who do this or approve this
torture and then there's no charges for
them it's simply because they say it's
happening outside of US borders in our
jurisdiction it's really a hypocrisy and
for someone like you who has exposed
such a significant crime which is
against American law international law
the you know human chart the the the
Human Rights Charter and you know
everywhere in the world countries sign
up to treaties that something like this
should not happen and here you are you
point out the truth you tell the world
about these atrocities and terrible
crimes and as anyone other than you been
in jail for the US government torture
program no no the torturers are free the
the men who came up with the torture
program are free the attorneys who
justified it her freed the people who
implemented it are free even the CIA
officers who murdered prisoners during
the course of the interrogations are
free I'm the only one that was ever
prosecuted and the psychologists who
were the architects of the program have
just signed to Cash Suman to avoid going
to trial for it to make that word
that cash settlement is being paid to
the victims by the American taxpayers
because in 2001 the CIA indemnified the
psychologist and the CIA agreed to pay
all of their legal expenses and any
settlement that might come out of the
case and they had already made I think
it was reported something like 46
million dollars 881 million dollars 81
million dollars so that's the price tag
to design something so sick and twisted
yes from the small amount of information
we know from the Senate torture report
which is under severe lock and key and
which the agencies are doing absolutely
everything they can to never allow that
full report to be accessible accessed by
the public but from what little we do
know in there
apparently they specifically recruited
CIA torturers who had a history of
domestic and sexual violence you know it
takes a special kind of monster to be
able to inflict that kind of physical
and psychological and emotional harm on
a person and not lose his soul you have
to have no soul in the first place
enabled in order to be able to do
something like that I think a really
relevant question for New Zealanders
John and light of recent events to ask
you is are you aware of New Zealand or
Australian troops
Anzac troops as we know special forces
being involved in extraordinary
renditions the reason I ask you this is
because it has recently come to light
that they were and initially we were
told that they it was revealed that they
were involved in handing detainees over
to foreign forces who they knew would
torture them
just a moment of caution here this is
very important John don't say anything
that could get you in legal trouble
again you need to be very careful in
answering these questions I don't want
you to say anything that is going to get
you in legal trouble yeah yeah thank you
can
I appreciate that is fine I definitely
don't have to give specific knowledge
that you have but just in theory the
reason I ask is because recently it has
been revealed and the famous
investigative journalist Nicky hoggers
book hit and run that New Zealand forces
have been involved in massacring unarmed
civilians in Afghanistan including women
and children and revenge rates that were
launched upon villages that supposedly
contain militants that it turned out
they didn't they killed them all and
burned all the houses down as literally
revenge rate I'm so I'm very interested
to know if you're aware of forces other
than of Allied American forces that
allied to the Americans also being
involved in extraordinary renditions I'm
not to tell you the truth certainly I
never ever encountered a New Zealander
when I was in the region and even the
Australians when I was in Pakistan and
we captured an Australian national the
Australians jumped up and down because
they wanted him to be turned over to
Australia immediately rather than to go
to Guantanamo
so no I'm glad to say I never
encountered any Australian or New
Zealand military officials intelligence
officials nobody involved in this kind
of thing considering everything else
they'd been involved in yeah I actually
hadn't heard that about the villagers
it's it's often it's true it's it's a
it's a war crime
it is literally a war crime and it's one
that the New Zealand government have
gone to quite some links to try to cover
up there are calls for a public inquiry
into what happened and the government is
resisting those holding that inquiry yes
yeah of course and I've gone to some
lengths as well to attempt to discredit
the authors of the book even
though they are unimpeachable as per
their record so we don't know yet what
will come of that that there are
certainly people in New Zealand who are
fighting very hard to get the truth out
there about what has happened and about
our involvement in those crimes
okay Kim do you have anything else that
you want to ask John I think we'll go to
Q&A shortly because I know there's been
a number of questions asked yes and I
still have a couple of things actually
yeah John I really want to pick your
brains because you know you're one of
the guys was inside for such a long time
and you know your understanding of the
intelligence community is priceless so
if you don't mind I have a couple of
questions just like the dark sides right
that they used outside of US borders to
torture people they are also using the
five eyes partner countries like New
Zealand Australia the UK and Canada to
spy on Americans where the u.s.
themselves legally is not permitted to
do that and then through xkeyscore and
all these other programs they get access
to that information anyway so they
outsource the spying to these other
countries on Americans and at the same
time the US by agencies give those
foreign agencies access to their own
fiber network give them access to all
the backdoors all the tools that they
have developed and then through the
backdoor
they are spying and mass on Americans
which is a breach of the Constitution
and u.s. law is that kind of a good
description of what went on to
circumvent any kind of prosecution in
torture cases is this how spy agencies
what you would say in your experience
operate if they have a challenge
nationally and it's against the Lord and
they will utilize friendly nation
and their agencies to still do it and
circumvent the law absolutely yes this
is the nature of our spy agencies you
have a CIA the CIA's culture is such
that it will push the bounds of legality
until it is slapped down and told to
stop when we've gone through these
periods in modern American history where
we have had strong oversight committees
for example 1975 to 1981 where we had
Frank church chairing the the first
Senate Intelligence Committee and Otis
Pike chairing the House Intelligence
Committee those were strong overseers
and then during the Reagan
administration we had weak overseers
well frankly since September 11th I
wouldn't even say that the that the
intelligence committees our oversight
committees I would say that their
cheerleading committees because they
just cheer on anything the CIA proposes
to do and in many cases the CIA doesn't
even bother to inform the committee's
what it's doing the committee's have to
find these things out from the press and
so the short answer to your question
chemists is yes that's exactly what
they're doing they're using any means at
their disposal to spy on American
citizens and to allow foreign
intelligence services to spy on American
citizens on their own behalf I agree
with you that it is illegal it's
unconstitutional it's illegal it's
unethical in fact it's even a violation
of the NSA Charter which specifically
says that NSA is forbidden under any
circumstances to spy on American
citizens but it happens every single day
in post 9/11 America yeah so with this
serial law-breaking going on and a new
president in the White House why don't
you think that Trump is doing something
about this why don't you think that you
know anyone new in charge this new
government isn't going in and saying hey
wow we are doing all these things and
this is all unlawful how come the one is
cracking down on the stuff you know I
never believed in the idea the notion of
a deep state well then let me correct
that sure there's a deep state sure but
I never believed in the notion that it
controlled the modes of government until
now yeah you know and now I mean it's
it's like not even deep anymore it's
it's out to sea it's like they're not
even they're not even afraid to be
identified as the deep state any and
they don't even have to make an effort
anymore because the media is so involved
it's what they're all lemmings there are
things and they go right off the cliff
with the with the lead lemming I you
know I'm gonna preface these comments by
saying I think I think Donald Trump is a
madman I think he's he's unfit mentally
emotionally and intellectually to be
president I think this is one of the his
election is one of the greatest mistakes
that Americans have made in modern times
with that said he believes that there's
a deep state and he believes that
they're out to get him in addition to
being out there to get other other
people well they're showing the whole
world that they are out to get him
I mean what's going on with with the
mass leaking with the liberal news media
attacking him I mean I get what you're
saying about him but he is one important
thing that I think has happened in the
United States you know more and more
people are becoming aware of how they
are constantly being lied to
they're becoming aware of government
abuse they're becoming aware that they
are really just being used that they are
not
electing politicians to serve them but
politicians only serve their own
interests and the interests of their
rich donors so in Donald Trump
I believe Americans have seen an
outsider who is not part of that
establishment who even amongst other
rich people is not really welcome
because of his attitude and his ego and
his I'm doing it my way attitude right
so in a way his election was I would say
the desperate effort by people you know
who see what's going on to have someone
completely outside of the political
establishment to come in and to change
something
the one on drain the swamp he want one
unlock her up you know people want to
have a president in the White House even
a character like Trump who's going to go
in and change all of this stuff you know
and it's so frustrating to see how
easily the deep state is just
manipulating everything and I am pretty
sure if Trump doesn't get bold
if he doesn't expose the crimes that
have been done by the deep state under
Obama the mass surveillance the breaches
of the constitutions the the breaches
mass breaches of law if he doesn't drain
the swamp as he said he'll be gone gone
before the end of the year everything is
building up to an event where he is
being removed as a president of the
United States and the longer he is
inactive his inaction is going to get
people to agree with that and not you
know be part of of the group that is
going to fight against his removal so I
think you know it's it's a great
opportunity for the you
to have a change agent even a person
like Trump who you know I agree with you
has an enormous ego you know does does
things in a way that you know you and I
wouldn't do but at the same time he is a
victim to the deep stage just like us
he is definitely right now a victim and
his opportunity is to go in there find
out everything that they've done expose
it and use this law breaking to reform
the intelligence community and the deep
state and expose what Obama and his
people have done to undermine the rights
of their citizens because that in itself
I think is the most powerful heroic
thing that he could do no one would care
any more about his ego and about you
know how important it is for him to have
won this election and for him to be
president if he did that you know we
could have a reset we could have a
restart of all of these institutions to
be serving the American citizens without
undermining the laws and undermining
their rights and frankly taking their
rights away more and more you know don't
you agree that that Trump could be that
change agents simply because of him not
being part of this establishment yet I
actually do agree with that the the
problem I think is that he has he has
become so deeply mired in domestic
problems of his own making witness this
white supremacy insanity that we're
going through right now that it might be
a problem
but but yeah I think you're exactly
right see this is the problem this is
the problem with my friends on the Left
I I'm a third generation Democrat until
my arrest and I left the Democratic
Party over this and our lifelong
progressive
Barack Obama should have been a
legendary hero for all of us and instead
Barack Obama was the one who took away
our rights yes civil rights are civil
liberties in many cases are human rights
and so you're right Kim that at least on
the international stage Donald Trump can
rehabilitate himself by by giving us
back our rights and standing up to the
deep state that Obama nurtured and built
yeah I believe that and you know that is
that is that is sorry go ahead
how did it happen that Bush who
instituted the torture program that your
case was dropped under Bush you see ya
then was brought back was reopened under
mr. hope and change Obama does this mean
that Obama was just a figurehead how is
it that Obama mr. hope and change became
the persecuted grand persecutor of
whistleblowers well I think that it's
actually darker than the idea of Obama
being a figurehead I mean I'll give you
two different answers one is a quick one
there was a book that was published in
2013 called double down by Mark Halperin
and John Holliman two noted political
commentators and in this book President
Obama sat for an interview and he said
two things that were really chilling to
me
one very matter-of-factly he said in
response to a question I never said I
was a liberal it's it's as though we
were tricked into thinking that he was
progressive the other thing he was
talking about the drone program and he
said I never had any idea that I would
be so good at killing people well that's
that's not something to brag about or to
marvel over I mean look at look at
george w bush's last month as president
and in george w bush's last month as
president he took actions that resulted
in the deaths of two people with the use
of the drone in Barack Obama's last
month as president he killed 424 people
with drones but how is that liberal
how is that progressive the other thing
is and and we've seen this through
modern history in the in the states with
inexperienced presidents the CIA loves
an inexperienced president social
engineering John because they send
socially and to do what they want that's
exactly it it's social engineering they
know that they can mold this guy into
their own image and so here you have a
president who has just been elected with
literally zero national security
experience he's he's elected but not yet
inaugurated and so they bring him into
the fold they give him access to the the
most closely held secrets they show him
the the blue border reports the black
border reports that are five and six
levels above top-secret and they say mr.
president-elect we want to tell you all
the cool things were doing overseas well
then they have him they've recruited him
they've made him one of the guys he's in
the club now and once he's in the club
he'll do anything they want
yeah well Trump's not in the club and
they don't want him in the club and he
don't want it because he's the deep
state wanted to get Hillary to win more
than anything because they know with her
it would have been the next four years
the next eight years just like under
Obama she is correctly complicit in all
of it they don't have to worry that any
of their illegalities are ever going to
come to light she's just going to cover
it up because she's part of this illegal
conspiracy that they have going and
Trump it's nothing more than a risk to
them they they don't like him they want
him gone
and I don't think Trump is someone who
can be socially engineered yes you know
they prefer keeping him in the dark and
and telling him almost nothing because
they are worried that if he understands
what really happened in the United
States under Obama
that he is going to stop that that he's
going to expose that and say guys what
are you doing you know the people didn't
sign up for that they didn't vote us in
so you can do this stuff and that's what
they are worried about and let me give
you a very big example of that just
before Obama less left office I don't
know if you probably read that in the
news the NSA went to the FISA Court and
the White House and the NSA admitted
that they have been spying on Americans
and they didn't really provide any
detail on how many and they as I usually
do make it sound like incidental and
accidental but they basically admitted
that they acted unlawfully spying on
Americans and then on the next page
they're saying but now that we know that
we did that we deleted everything we
just went into our databases found
everything that we captured that we
shouldn't have and we deleted it and
what did they delete Hillary Clinton's
emails from her private email server and
everything else that has happened in the
Obama administration that could come and
haunt them because these emails as you
well know as you know an expert in the
intelligence community were hoovered up
by the NSA spy systems automatically you
know doesn't even require an agent to do
it Todd by targeting her that happen
automatically because it was a private
server it was not a state email system
so they Hoover it all up they have it in
the Utah spy cloud and then they went to
Pfizer just before Obama is gone to get
permission or basically to tell the FISA
Court
we've now deleted all the stuff that
we're not supposed to have that's how
they cover things up I mean it's
incredible
how how openly they do it you know and
for someone who understands how they
work when you read this stuff you just
go well why didn't the FISA Court say
hey hold on a minute preserve this as
evidence if you say you did this
unlawfully well someone needs to
investigate it someone needs to look at
it but you have these FISA Court judges
that really just rub us them everything
that I see puts to them and they are not
interested in any kind of investigation
because it makes themselves look bad but
someone like Trump could appoint a
special prosecutor to look in into the
mass constitutional breaches of the spy
agencies he could you know have sessions
through that in a heartbeat that's what
they are worried about and what they are
doing right now is try and get as rid of
as much of the evidence as they can
because you know if they fail in the
Coweta of Donald Trump if they can't
remove him you know they are risking
that they will be seriously exposed
because I believe that Donald Trump
would be taking action if he had a full
picture of what really went on on during
the Obama years I would agree with that
I think he does not have a full picture
you know another thing to think of too
is the CIA the NSA all the intelligence
agencies are our civil service agencies
people are there for 20 25 30 35 years
at a time and so the leaders inside the
CIA with the exception of the director
himself everybody else from the Deputy
Director level all the way down came of
age in the Obama administration they're
all Obama holdovers this is very much
Barack Obama's CIA that's exactly right
and there are so many Obama loyalists
still there
and they know what they have done they
know if ever there was a real
investigation into their activities they
would all go to jail or they should
without the I am copper up mode and they
are trying still now to prevent this
president because they are scared of him
exactly right yeah and you can say
whatever you want about Trump that is a
quality that he has and a potential that
he has where I just haven't joined the
group of people that said are Trump is
horrible and this and that because he as
crazy as it is is our best hope to get
something changed because he's on our
side he himself is exposed to this third
it's true it's true and it is pointing
because they have so bottled him up
politically yeah and again a lot of this
is of his own making because he does not
have Washington experience but they have
so bottled him up politically that he's
focused now solely on saving himself and
his agenda and on domestic issues when
was the last time Donald Trump said
anything about mass surveillance I can't
even remember yeah well I mean the only
person who says something about it is
Sean Hannity Sean Hannity on Fox he
talks about the deep state all the time
and it's it's Trump's favorite programs
I'm pretty sure he's much more aware
about the issues now than he was when he
got elected and you know if I was from
and I put myself into his shoes right
and I have all these leaks coming out
hundreds hundreds of leaks my
transcripts of phone calls with foreign
leaders and then the intelligence
community which has only one purpose is
to protect my information
can find and produce a single liquor
can't stop the leaking I mean how dumb
do you have to be not to understand that
it's them who's doing it you know it's
them was doing it no one is going to be
found out and it's because they don't
like this president they want to get rid
of Trump at all costs and you know to me
personally I think there is an
opportunity here you know if this
president understands that his enemy is
also our enemy and is also the enemy of
the American people and the American
dream and the future of America once he
understands that I'm thinking and I'm
thinking is on the way to getting that
you know there is a real opportunity to
change this thing I think that is a
brilliant op-ed everything that you just
said is true and important and it's
something that the American people are
simply not focused on yeah you're right
this the deep State the intelligence
apparatus the intelligence and the
federal law enforcement apparatus are
the enemies of the American people and
the American dream
yeah and you know the good thing is even
within those dire times where all these
crimes are being committed there are
people like you with a moral compass you
know who think ethics are something to
cherish who will work with WikiLeaks
with the media to put these stories out
there and if there's one trend that is
really encouraging then it's the amount
of people that are coming forward with
information you know it is increasing
Snowden has opened the floodgates and
now everyone who
is aware of these criminal acts you know
has to ask ask themselves their own
conscience you know is this something I
want to continue doing or do I want to
join forces with people like charm of
people like add with the CIA
whistleblower who's giving WikiLeaks all
the stuff the world 7 stuff the media
ops that are coming out everything that
is coming out right these people right
now have an opportunity to reform what's
happening in the deep state they have an
opportunity to release as much as they
can so that the president has a chance
to point the finger at it and to change
this because if we don't take this
opportunity now that doesn't happen now
I don't think we will get another
opportunity there's now a global arms
race in the intelligence world every
country wants to have the kind of powers
that the US has it's going to be used
more and more radically to to cut down
on the sand to silence people that are
not in the interest of a particular
government and you know now it's the
time we really have to do something with
urgency here and as crazy as it sounds
Trump is probably the best guy to do it
that you're correct that probably the
only way out of the hole that he's in
right now would be for Trump himself to
blow the whistle and for him to blow the
whistle on the Obama government on the
pace of play of the Clinton Foundation
and die Clinton and Diet Debbie
wasserman-schultz event and that's what
promised Americans and if he doesn't do
it if he doesn't do it in the end price
for impeachment are coming it will come
before the end of this year if he
doesn't do it he'll be gone no one would
care about fighting for him if he
doesn't deliver
on those promises I think your theory is
brilliant and I and I genuinely hope
that he takes that advice that he has
the strength and the integrity to take
that advice however I've got a few
doubts first is that he is so completely
surrounded by generals and that he's
surrounded by generals who are complicit
and a lot of what has happened
particularly in the Wars of the last 15
years and I think the reason he's being
surrounded by those generals is for him
to be taken into the fold
that's like Plan B plan one is get rid
of him you know plan two is try to get
him still on to their side so that's the
first thing that I would say the second
thing is I think that this is not just a
lift right war or in a deep state versus
people war it's a class war and when you
look at the photos of Hillary Clinton
and of Trunk together of which there are
many while he may not be an insider he
certainly walked in those circles for
long enough and there is a difference
between the haves and have-nots in that
sense and he will side with his class
against the the majority of the people
so what I see is that it's more like
competing mafia clans it's like the
Clinton clan is like a mafia and Trump's
crowd is like a mafia and they're
fighting it out and having their mafia
war together within government I also
see that Trump is in charge of the
police state he has all of the police
unions and agencies and everything
rooting for him and then Clinton if you
look at she was pushing TPP TPP was
signed on to by all the heads of the
intelligence agencies they all wanted it
to pass so Trump coming in and ditching
the TPP basically on day one would have
put him on their list as well from
that point so what we have now is the
police state versus the intelligence
agencies and while Trump is leading the
police state Trump will never be for the
people who are on the ground because
that is the police state who enforce the
mechanisms of control above and over the
people who are on the ground so we had
this this weird conflict is created like
this bipolar and society almost that you
see at the moment where actually to be
honest with you neither side is great
the police agencies
massive problems and corruption racism
systemic corruption systemic issues
oppression of people's and of activists
and then the intelligence agencies are
just like Nix liberal worst of all like
the stuff that they've been involved in
from war crimes to extraordinary
renditions to torture to everything else
they are the worst of the worst so now
we have like would you like to support
the system of domestic oppression or
would you like to support the system of
international oppression and that's the
choice that's being sold to people I
also say that I'm completely disgusted
with liberals I come from an activist
background I'm still an activist to this
day I find it incredible that there are
activists out there who have been
targeted by the intelligence agencies
and their movements have been targeted
by the intelligence agencies for the
last six years and decades before that
they have been personally targeted and
oppressed by Obama's administration and
by Hillary Clinton who are now saying oh
the CIA is not that bad all the
intelligence agencies aren't that bad
actually you know they're trying to do a
good thing getting rid of Trump yeah I
think we'll match with them everything's
fine
you have people like at Thunder on
Twitter who literally says I am the
leader of the resistance
he is the funder for Hillary Clinton
literally the funder for the Democratic
Party and he claims to be an activist
leading the resistance his party has
just spent the last six years I've been
an activist targeting and undermining
and destroying the lives of the
activists that they now claim to be
marching with against Trump so it is a
complete and utter fast and anybody who
will get in bed with Hillary Clinton and
her financial backers and the
intelligence agencies and then call
themselves an activist needs a wake-up
call if you are going to be an activist
at least be on principle but if you are
marching alongside Hillary Clinton and
her cronies you are nothing but a
people's front forward the Clinton mafia
so that's my two cents and on the other
side if you are marching with the
National Front and David Juke well don't
be surprised that people are calling you
a Nazi
or racist because you've got no business
matching with those people and calling
yourself an activist either and I'm sure
I will lose a lot of friends by pointing
this out but what I'm saying is that
both sides are corrupt or isn't then
what Trump said it's like that with
Trump said neither side has the moral
high ground at all yeah now I am aware
that there are very legitimate activist
organizations who are smart enough to
not have fallen for the lift versus
right to ride buses Concord Clinton
versus Trump for intelligence agencies
versus police agencies that is the
anti-war movement that is the legitimate
legitimate peace protesters they do not
side with either the left or the right
and they are genuinely working for peace
for the planet they want to shut down
the nukes they want to shut down the
torture they want to shut down the
extraordinary renditions they're
fighting to shut down the drone programs
and you don't hear those people going
yeah let's go punch a Nazi and you don't
hear them going always you know kill the
Liberals they're not starting militias
they are genuinely involved in a
movement for peace those are the same
people those are the people who we need
to support world beyond war go and check
them out these are the real activists
the activists who are not aligned with
either side these are the people who
wish and support so that's my two cents
on that now just to switch topics on you
really quickly and John I want to just
talk about quickly sanctioned leaks
versus unsanctioned leagues because it
seems to me that people like you get in
a lot of trouble for telling the truth
but then we have people like well Bob
Woodward was specifically who I wanted
to talk about Bob Woodward is a very
very famous political author and he has
written books about a series of American
presidents and I'm just quickly going to
share my screen and show you something
that I have here on Twitter is for much
of this year it's a quote from Bob
Woodward and the quotes is I have had
presidents in Republican and Democrat
administrations provide information that
is technically classified
bill he's talking to Bill O'Reilly bill
you know that happens all of the time
and that's Bob Woodward now Bob Woodward
wrote the books about with super books
that bushes was and also book about
Obama when I read those books I couldn't
do as a few things in them that I
literally had my mouth hanging open I
actually sent these to Glenn Greenwald a
few quotes a few years back and a few
other people because they really shocked
me so the first thing that really
shocked me is the the names of the
program's CIA programs names of systems
details of technical systems that and
the the frameworks by which military
operations are conducted in Afghanistan
you can find these in these books you
can find d2 operational details you can
find very specific testimony from and
from even named people and unnamed
sources about things that are happening
inside the agencies and these books sell
millions of copies and end up on the New
York Times is sellers list and also as
he said himself he's received class
technically classified information from
presidents on both sides but then there
was also a story in there that really
shocked me those two stories that really
shocked me one was they were talking
about how the CIA wanted to get an
Afghan warlord onto their side so they
went and offered him a cash bribe of
however much money and the warlord said
no thank you
I don't want to accept the money and so
the CIA said well what should we do
about that I know we'll drop a 50,000
pound bomb outside his compound and then
we'll go back to him the next day and
offer him less money so they dropped a
fifty thousand pound bomb outside his
compound which I mean you you might have
some idea of how much it costs to buy a
fifty thousand pound bomb I have no idea
I just think it's morally reprehensible
that they would do such thing sure
enough they went back to him afterwards
and offered him half the cash he
accepted the deal so this is the kind of
thing that there seems to be going on
within these agencies and that they
think is okay for them to expend
munitions purchase some public dollars
to scare the out of people so that
they will it take exactly
money the second story from Bob
Woodward's books which I found
absolutely unbelievable was a story in
Iraq and believe what summer in the
Kurdish border and they were saying they
were talking about how they had a CIA se
inside this building this compound where
these bad guys were and the CIA s it was
reporting to giving them information
from within and so they went to blow up
the compound but they said to themselves
well we did not tell our asset that
we're going to blow up the compound that
he's in in case there's you know it
exposed us somehow so we'll just blow it
up with him in it and that's what they
did they leveled the place and killed
their own essage and I could not believe
they were they would write about this
first of all that they do it
second of all that they would write
about it in a Bob Woodward New York
Times bestseller so I'd like to know
what is what do you have to say about
this this this manifestation of these
like horrific war stories and those
highly classified information in books
that sell millions of copies and make
millions of dollars whereas you told the
world that war crimes have been
committed and you end up in jail
why is Bob Woodward not in jail you're
muted John
John you're on mute alright I'm amused
that you're surprised by any of this
the CIA has been doing these that kinds
of things since its creation in 1947 let
me tell you a short anecdote - after the
episode ADA capture I told you I was
promoted and named executive assistant
to the deputy director I had a lovely
private office with brand new expensive
furniture and I was enjoying my office
and sitting there like this one day and
I happened to be turned and looking past
the secretary into the hallway I had a
direct line of sight into the hallway
and as I'm sitting there like this
looking Bob Woodward walks past the door
without a security expert sorry a
security escort and I said to the
secretary was that Bob Woodward that
just walked past the door from the
Washington Post and she said yeah I said
what in the world is Bob Woodward doing
walking the halls and she said oh you
didn't see the memo the director gave
him free access and we're all ordered to
cooperate with him and I thought man so
that's how the game is played when you
want to get the official story out there
you can leak to your heart's content
because it makes the CIA look good it
makes the White House look good and it
makes the Pentagon look good and that's
what they want at the same time the
White House and its employees are the
most prolific leakers in all of
government they leak for a variety of
reasons they leak to make the president
look good they may lead to make him look
strong they leak to to create trial
balloons just to see what the public
reaction would be to something to some
policy change or or or nomination that
they're considering we also need to
remember that there's a difference
between leaking and whistleblowing
whistleblowing is bringing to light any
evidence of waste fraud
abuse illegality or threats to the
public health or public safety leaking
is leaking and people leak for a variety
of reasons they leak to make themselves
seem important
they leak to to help to quench this this
need for for the thrill of leaking or a
thrill of being in contact with a
reporter sometimes they'll leak for
revenge maybe they don't like a
president or a boss or they've been
passed over for promotion and they'll
the leak just to get revenge on whoever
it is they believe wronged them but
that's not whistle blown it's the
whistle blowers that the administration
is afraid of because it's the whistle
blowers who are the truth tellers that's
what they're worried about they don't
want the American people to know the
truth about these programs because these
programs most of them are patently
illegal and in many cases or even
violations of international law that's
what they're afraid of so yeah you know
I read all those books too I've read
every book that Bob Woodward's written I
read Jane Mayer's brilliant books and
they are chock full of classified
information those books would fall apart
if they didn't have classified
information but that's classified
information that has come as a result of
official leaks SEC sanctions absolutely
so you talk about the media being
important for us to rage but so often
they work in concert to promote war yes
and to suppress dissent so to what
extent were the rank-and-file CIA
personnel aware of their agency having
infiltrated the news media as women
we've heard about this you know from
mockingbirds onwards for decades we've
heard about this there's been a variety
of releases on WikiLeaks about this
topic so is this Noren with an agency
that the CIA has media cutouts and how
does what is the information flow from
from the agency to media channels well a
lot of that is actually class
I probably shouldn't get into specifics
but you know operation Mockingbird
really did end at least at least as it
was targeting American journalists but
as you might imagine a journalists
foreign journalists all around the world
are targeted that's that's just the
nature of intelligence and the nature of
journalism it's not specific to the CIA
every Intelligence Service does that
kind of thing because that's how you
control the debate it's just a natural
thing to do
so yeah sure I mean every CIA officer
knows the history of operation
Mockingbird every CIA officer knows that
somewhere in the world journalists are
on the CIA payroll placing stories that
the CIA wants to be placed that's that's
just intelligence that's the way it is
what was even oh yeah the CIA
invests into an entrepreneur six hundred
million dollars and then half that
entrepreneur by The Washington Post and
directly influence what the Washington
Post is talking about I mean the
Washington Post has become such a
cover-up Organization for all of these
crimes
you might recall recently some emails
were published where you know things
came out about the Hillary campaign and
and stuff and then the reporters would
write to Hillary to the to the people in
her campaign and say we're really sorry
that we have to ask this stuff kind of
you know bowing bowing down and and
saying you know we don't like to report
but we have to ask some questions and
that's the culture today you know that
these large media organizations they are
all run by money and in times where
advertising income evaporates and they
don't really do
as well as they did before the Internet
you know they are trying to find ways to
survive and part of survival is to
partner with companies with you know
powerful people that will keep them
afloat and when Trump says the failing
almost broke New York Times is
absolutely right you know they don't
even know how they're going to have
enough money next year to pay all their
stuff so you know they're working with
with people that have a certain agenda
and they feed them and keep them alive
and a lot of that I believe is going to
come out and future WikiLeaks releases
called neots and it's also showing how
deeply the CIA and other agencies have
infiltrated the news media and not just
that you know it's one has to wonder how
does the CIA and then it's a half all
these backdoors they don't have them
into our technologies and our devices
because they sit like a hacker would at
home and and they try and find the back
doors they've try and find the
vulnerabilities in the software they
planted themselves that is the way
they're doing it now they have their own
people within Microsoft with an apple
within Google
you know implementing into the source
code often without the knowledge of
these corporations implementing
backdoors that allow these spy agencies
later to turn these devices into open
mics into open cameras and that's the
scary stuff the spy agencies went from
well how can we take advantage of what's
out there and make it work for us to
let's make it work for us let's put our
own people in there and let's manipulate
everything and this is the word we're
living in if you read a news story on
the New York Times of Washington Post
you
have to ask yourselves to someone you
know who is part of the media ops
program of the deep state when you when
you install your Windows software or you
boot up your iPhone you have to wonder
how many people does actually take to
have a backdoor to turn my phone into an
open mic it's really just one person one
lead developer who puts a piece of code
into this enormous universe of code that
will give me another backdoor and they
planned hundreds of those and by doing
it they are not only undermining our
trust in the media and into these
technology companies but they are giving
the enemy a powerful tool to strike
against us because these vulnerabilities
that have been created they leak somehow
like the entire NSA hacking toolkit that
was leaked not too long ago and now the
enemy has that organized crime has that
you know countries that are not friends
of the u.s. at all have access to that
and now they can use it to harm American
citizens and this is you know if Trump
would understand that the significance
the magnitude of how they are weakening
the security structure of the United
States by doing this stuff if he would
understand that I think he's the one guy
who we can hope will do something about
it you know but that's what's going on I
mean that is how everything is being
manipulated now and I know that with
first and experience from my case and
discovery that we had and the research
that I've done and I have a data
security background so I understand very
well how they are doing it and you know
it is very important that more and more
people come forward and release their
programs if you follow the wall
seven releases you know every week or
two Julian that's another document come
out you know it's incredible the amount
of backdoors that they have now into our
daily lives every internet router is you
know an open door to them every
operating system no matter if it's
Windows Linux or you know Macintosh
every mobile phone from every
manufacturer no matter what operating
system they use it's ridiculous who gave
them the right to do that
you know nobody signed up for that if
the American people you know what would
really understand what's going on and
were asked if they if they accept that
if they agree with that they would say
no if they were asked to vote in a
president who's going to turn that
off they will vote for him right that's
exactly right
and as crazy as this may sound Trump
might be our best hope you know but
here's the there in reality okay I mean
they're really just three options from
number one he becomes an ally and he
works with them and he allows them to
social engineer him into compliance like
they have done with Obama and every
president after Kennedy okay that's
number one number two he's going to war
there will be some bigger news event
that is just going to quiet down
everything else they will try and get
him engaged in some kind of war
this whole bombing of the Syrian
airfield which dominated the news for a
week that was really just give me a
breather I need some space you know and
the third option and that is you know
the Kennedy option is if they can't make
it work with him and force him into
compliance you know they were either
kill him or you know if impeachment
doesn't work
they would they will get rid of him you
know so if I was Trump my best option
would be to really expose what is
happening here to bring all these crimes
to light and to shut these things down
and reform those agencies and he will
become a hero for generations and all
the young people that are following all
the stuff that are fed up with fake news
that know what's going on you know he's
going to become the hero no matter left
or right you know he can do what's right
the right thing and that is the
opportunity and that's why I supported
him because I saw just like brexit
that's not what the establishment wants
the establishment wanted to stay in the
European Union establishment didn't want
Trump to win they don't want these
forces that interfere with their
globalist agenda and you know the plans
that they have so that's why I supported
him because he is a punishment for those
who have done this through the world for
the last few decades you know my only
disappointment with him in that respect
though was his appointment of Michael
Pompeo as the CIA director because
Pompeo is completely these are
completely establishment man use he's a
West Point graduate he was a Republican
and conservative Republican congressman
from Kansas he was on the House
Intelligence Committee we're not going
to get any outside the box thinking from
the likes of Mike Pompeo and then to
make matters worse when Pompeo became
director rather than pulling his deputy
director from let's say the Republican
staff on the committee he named Gina
Haspel the CIA's deputy director Gina
Haskell who was one of the original
creators of the CIA's torture program so
that was a disappointment to me because
he could have made a bowl
nomination which would have really been
a very important statement to the
establishment and he didn't it but you
know what the problem is he doesn't know
he doesn't understand what's going on he
doesn't know what you know I know or
Julien know in the news and then he gets
you know a certain percentage of it but
he doesn't really understand it I mean
his age history he is not an Internet
guy he is not a technology guy you know
his mind is it's not structured to
understand these things unless someone
who he can trust who understands these
things can talk to him and explain it to
him and point him at evidence and show
him what's really happening that is the
biggest problem but you know there are
people out there there are voices out
there that he listens to that are
pointing these things out to him and
that's where the opportunity is because
if he gets it that's what I believe
if he gets what's going on he will want
to do something about it he will not be
complicit in this type of stuff that is
my that is my personal belief and I know
you know a lot of people might disagree
but when I saw Trump you know having a
chance to become the president and how
the establishment had an allergic
reaction to him I knew that he could be
the guy you know he could be the guy to
to blow this all open and to reform it
all and it's a it's a huge opportunity
for him to make history
you know because what's happening right
now in the United States is not in the
service of the American people this is
all about money about economic control
you know this is not about our rights or
freedoms this is not about making
America great again or the American
dream it's all about selfish commercial
agendas
mm-hmm you know and the people are being
used and their rights are being trampled
on and the laws being broken on a daily
serial basis and that needs to stop and
I will not stop if people like you and I
and Julian and Edward and all the other
truth tellers out there are putting it
out there for everyone to understand and
you know what the people who get it our
numbers are growing you can see it in
the voting behavior already you can see
it you know people get it they want
change Obama got voted in for change and
hope and then disappointed everyone if
Trump does it again the next time
someone a complete outsider neither with
the Democrats or the Republicans is
going to get a boost there will be
someone coming out of MIT fear out of
nowhere where people will make an
investment of faith and and and Trust
and get that guy in simply because they
are fed up with the lies and with the
crimes the government is committing at
their expense you know so it's just a
matter of time as long as we keep
talking and we're building this momentum
on whether we are organizing and we're
talking about it you know sooner or
later this whole thing is going to fall
apart and that is the biggest fear you
know that's why they fear you that's why
they wanted to put you in skit in jail
for a decade because you know people
like you can change the whole game for
them they understand that one is that's
a really good call about Gina Halperin I
might be mispronouncing her name she's
also associated with the Saudis and when
we saw the Trump go straight to Saudi
Arabia and touch the orb and do the
sword dance and the whole rigmarole and
that this told us a lot you know the
whole christening of the Saudi and you
terrorists into and of course the Saudis
are behind a lot of the terrorism in the
world so he definitely has people around
him who were trying to subvert him for
the establishment interest also we
cannot ignore that bitsy divorce of BT's
of us again I might be
her name is the sister of eric prince
who is also at Trump's table
Eric Prince is owned Blackwater and
which has had a few name changes since
then he is the king of mercenary armies
in all of the war zones across the world
and also attempting to make money on the
militarization of the domestic police
forces in America so once again I am
with you Kim that I would love Trump to
be the one be the near you know to like
blow it all open get the truth out there
and change the system that the people
who are around him are the same toxic
militarists that have been involved in
previous administrations you know I
might be completely wrong and completely
naive about it but you know when I see
an opportunity you know when I see even
a 10% chance that by them cornering him
and alienating him and putting him in a
situation where it's you know his
downfall or theirs that he might do the
right thing that he might understand how
he can escape this and how he can put
them on on the spot you know and if he
does that he might actually survive all
of this deep state collusion to get him
out and if he does you know he might
actually become a hero who knows I mean
Trump is definitely someone who would
love to be everybody's hero he loves to
be loved okay so if you watch this
Donald if you want to be loved
cut this crime down you know drain the
swamp do what you promised everyone
that's what we want what the whole world
is waiting for that is what we hope for
when Obama told us about the change you
know this is your opportunity don't be
like everyone else don't be a loser of
the deep state you know do your own
thing and be your own man and beat them
down with us with our help right right
let's go I
I hate them there's absolutely no doubt
about that they have used the entire
mass media to try to make everyone else
hate them as well so he's definitely a
victim in that sense and being
persecuted by them in that sense they do
say the truth will set you free
hopefully he will find it within himself
to tell the truth on an epic never
before seen scale I I do hope that and
actually then his only real safety
mechanism would be the support of the
public okay I just want to address a
concern that I have really quickly about
some of the comments that I say one more
thing one more thing sue that the first
step that I would take if I was Donald
Trump was to would be true pardon Julian
lunch yes the end the persecution
against him and WikiLeaks and to send a
strong message that you know truth
tellers are not locked up or terrorized
with some fake charges you know if he
were to do that there would be a strong
signal and I think it would benefit him
greatly because Julian has a lot of
information that could be very helpful
to his presidency here WikiLeaks has
changed everything they've changed the
media landscape the political landscape
they have given people think John Pilger
I keep quoting John Pilger who says that
that WikiLeaks restored honor to
journalism they were instant restore
integrity to journalism they've raised
the bar for journalists around the world
I cannot imagine what the world would be
like without them and what it would have
been like without them have much further
we would have devolved as a society
without them so there are critical
importance and absolutely mean you can
see here to have my courage t-shirt off
I want you to support the courage
Foundation because they support the
whistleblowers that have worked with
WikiLeaks and/or had just made
significant contributions to a
historical record so please if you can
donate to WikiLeaks at wikileaks.org
slash donate and to the courage
foundation at courage founds org
these organizations are the lifeblood of
truth and in our society and the real
media and they hold both the media and
governments to account so please do
support them okay I just want to move on
quickly there is a couple of accounts I
actually follow and fairly regularly
retweet who have been making
discouragements about John because they
are saying how many people has John been
a part of torturing how many people has
John been complicit in the oppression of
and I would just like to make this point
to you guys now and this is an important
one that I don't want you to forget the
question is not how many people has John
been complicit in torturing the question
is how many people have not been
tortured as a result of John doing the
right thing and stepping up and telling
the entire world what was going on you
can sit here and blame the man for his
past or you can look at the choice that
he made and what we have all learned as
a result this is someone on our stream
who a President of the United States has
had to stand up and be accountable in
press conferences based on the
revelations that John has made when her
Obama said are we tortured some folks
and had to account for what they were
doing it was because of John's
disclosure so rather than looking at
what John did in the past you guys need
to look at the impact of what his
disclosures had and see the change that
has happened since because you can be
damn sure that there are CIA torturers
and interrogators who have had to think
twice about what they were doing when
they were doing it because of John
stepping up and you can also be damn
sure that there will be other
whistleblowers that will come forward
because of John he's already explained
to you about his letter that he wrote to
Snowden and what an impact that had on
Snowden the Snowden revelations may have
got as much air as they have got it
because of people like John so are you
going to say to it word Snowden how many
people did you spy on how many people
target you know when you're an NSA
employee or are you gonna say holy
it would Snowden you have changed the
world with your releases how many in is
a
sitting at their desk looking at targets
like I was a target in New Zealand like
Kim was a target in New Zealand they
used to spy on me through my cameras
these to spy on my kids in my house
how many NSA employees are sitting there
looking at targets like us activists
journalists entrepreneurs tick
visionaries and thinking I shouldn't be
doing this this is wrong this is
disgusting
we've already got the reality when a
case there's many other cases these
whistleblowers influenced millions of
people so do not sit there and ask
questions about how many people did john
torture ask how many CIA torturers are
shivving themselves now about what they
are doing because of the disclosures
that John is made but John yeah John has
made clear that one has made already
clear that he didn't torture anybody
that when he was asked that he refused
to be a part of that so to answer that
question more clearly Shawn has not been
involved in any kind of torture said
rights on that's that's right kid thank
you yeah I've never ever been involved
in any kind of torture not even
indirectly so you know so many people
have said so many ridiculous things
about me over the years I've developed a
very thick skin
what I object to what really makes me
sad is the ignorant of people who make
comments without having even even
educated themselves in the most basic
way on these issues or or on my own
history my entire life is out there on
the internet available for anybody who
cares so to ask a stupid question like
that it's just very sad
and often you need to keep in mind that
spy agencies have their own armadas of
online trolls trolls exactly that are
just doing their stuff on misinformation
all the time
I mean it's hilarious how openly that
can be found out and I have to say that
most of the followers that criticize me
on Twitter surprisingly always have less
than hundred followers you know it's the
little shits that make the loudest noise
and one has to wonder why there is
because people you know in the
statistics that I have reviewed you know
of hate speech online people who have
more than thousand followers and you
know who they are they usually don't
talk this kind of you know it's
it's mainly the small accounts that you
know it's it's really hard to tell well
who is this person when has he actually
tweeted about who's just retweeting
every now and then and the rest is just
eight speech again
again some people you know a lot of it
is just organized it's an effort to
undermine your credibility or the
credibility of whistleblowers in general
being employed against all of the
legitimate activists and activist
movements the people who I was calling
out specifically on the stream I won't
name them but they are anti-war activist
and I think what they are attempting to
do is to present John to indict John on
the basis of the activities of the CIA
as a whole to which I say to him you do
not blame the whistleblower for the
system that he blew the whistle on
simple they respect the whistleblower
and I'll bet you did it until the end of
time John because when you speak out and
you inform the public you are worthy of
our respect and you're worthy of our
things so I know it's like god knows
what time in the morning for you and I
know you must be so exhausted I also
know that there are hundreds of people
have been asking questions on social
media so I'm gonna ask Blake now what
about awesome
members to relay to you just a couple of
the best questions like and we'll have
John answer them and then we'll let him
go in and get some sleep
hey so I'd like to start with Jenny Lynn
because she's donated last time and this
time on the YouTube thank you um so she
asked she wants to know what else John
witnessed in the CIA Wow you know I I
reported I have to be extremely careful
with this I the the threat that I made
was not idle and so when I made that
threat through my attorneys I then went
to the Senate Intelligence Committee and
and reported it to the to the overseers
it had to do with financial crimes but I
and I apologized that I can't be more
specific but I should probably leave it
at that just to protect myself vehicle a
slider asks John the CIA drug trade
didn't suddenly in doubt in the Obama we
know the gun is running his being
privatized who's handling the drugs well
let me tell you a short anecdote from my
time on the Senate Foreign Relations
Committee staff and I'm gonna preface
this by saying that this is unclassified
because at the time that this happened I
did not have a security clearance nor
did I have access to classified
information in 2011 I took a trip to
Afghanistan for the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee I was doing research
for a paper on the heroin poppy trade
and
Afghanistan and I flew to Lush cargo
which is a city town a village whatever
it's a village in Helmand province and
it's the epicenter of the Afghan heroin
trade and I asked a poppy farmer a very
naive question I said why instead of
growing heroin poppy why don't you grow
crops that have two growing seasons why
don't you grow things like onions or
tomatoes or pomegranates or winter wheat
and he was exasperated and he exhaled
and said you know the CIA told me in
2001 that if I told them where the Arabs
were I could grow all the poppy I wanted
and now you come here and you tell me I
can't grow poppy and I said did the CIA
tell you you could grow poppy and as
soon as I asked that question my
military handler ended the interview and
that was the last I was able to say I
returned to Washington and I mentioned
this to my boss at the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee and he shook his
head and he said there's no way you're
gonna write a paper and say that and
that was the end of it so my own
educated guess is that the CIA's
involvement whether it's direct or
indirect with drugs has never ended
can I just kind of ask a really naive
question place what exactly is a
military Hendler why did you have one is
this a mandatory thing or just first
sudden rank or well know it because well
because Afghanistan is a war zone the
only way to get from point A to point B
is on a military aircraft and so Lashkar
Gah like many of the outlying posts
their State Department posts are their
only accessible by helicopter and so if
I want to go from Kabul or from Bagram
Air Base to Lashkar Gah or to anywhere
else in the country I mean you can't
just get in a car and drive you have to
be flown by military aircraft and so
that was it
thank you for that like let's say Jeremy
Walker asks
does kumkum and John have a Deadman
switch on their info
I'll give you the easy answer for myself
as I'm too stupid to even figure out how
to do a Deadman switch so my answers No
I never had one and one of the
justifications for the raid was that the
FBI told the New Zealand police that I
had a doomsday device and if I would
push the button it would delete over
2,000 servers around the world
containing all of mega uploads data and
no evidence has ever been provided of
any of that it was a complete
fabrication and I still don't have any
such device I'm an open book you know I
don't even mind when I write my messages
- you know numerous people that I'm
working with it they are all aware of
what I'm doing you know because I like I
like them to see that I'm fighting them
actively I like them to understand that
I'm not scared of them that I will
continue my fight and even though
privacy is very important when you do
what I do it's very difficult the effort
that is required to keep your
communications private when you are
watched by so many people that are
interested in you the effort just
becomes too big so I've just said you
know let my people in the NSA and in the
CIA and at the GCSB that are used to
living the life of others let them live
my life and I'm trying my best to
entertain them and to show them my
fighting spirit and that they can't
break me so you know for me personally I
made the fact that I have no privacy
anymore work I do not recommend it for
you know most people because it's not
the right thing you shouldn't have to
live in a world where you know that
everything you do is being scrutinized
but I made it work for myself
if Donald Trump we're sitting in front
of you right now
what would your elevator pitch for
granting your pardon be from MWD 503 7
who is also a donator well let me start
with that I would say first of all don't
pardon me because I'm just going to win
my case outright okay I have I have that
covered I have brilliant lawyers I've
done nothing wrong I'm going to beat
them even though John warned me that
they're going to kill me I'm going to
give them one hell of a fight and if
they if they ultimately succeed and
killing me
everyone is going to know that it is a
completely corrupt case I will make sure
of that but they Trump you should pardon
Julian Assange you should pardon
WikiLeaks because without Julian Assange
you wouldn't be President of the United
States right now and without him we
wouldn't know about all of these
government intrusions into our lives
about the legal conduct around the world
and you can't stand for that you can't
be part of that you can't become
complicit in these mass crimes that are
being committed around the world I do
believe that you have the best interest
of the American people at heart I do
believe that you want to do the right
thing to make America great again and
the deep state is one big obstacle to
making that happen because everything
that they are doing is damaging the
United States on the international stage
is damaging technology companies that
are being undermined to to backdoor them
is damaging the human rights of your of
your voters you know so by partying
pardoning Julian Assange you would do
the first step in the right direction
and then hopefully the information that
Julie
can provide you or a special prosecutor
appointed by your Attorney General is
going to allow you to reform the deep
state and to investigate all the crimes
that were committed during the Obama
years I actually do have an elevator
pitch but more than an elevator pitch
I've got a letter it's here in front of
me on my computer is signed by 77 former
CIA officers asking President Obama to
pardon me for a number of reasons I mean
they're they're kind of obvious we
talked about them tonight
that didn't happen my goal was to get in
front of Vice President Biden by the end
of the administration and to ask Biden
to go to bat for me because Biden was
one of only five senators only two of
whom are still living who voted against
enactment of the Intelligence identities
Protection Act which is what I was
convicted of violating through the
support of the Greek American community
here in the United States which is which
is very strong they've been standing
shoulder-to-shoulder with me for years
we did get in front of Vice President
Biden four days before the end of the
Obama administration and Biden agreed to
go to the president with one of these
Greek American businessmen and argue my
case that Greek American businessman
telephoned me at midnight after he had
walked out of the White House and he
said John you would have been so proud
of Vice President Biden he said he
argued your case for ten minutes and
went to the mat for you asking the
President to pardon you and in the end
he said the president looked at us and
said guys I'm just not going to do this
it's either him or it's Manning and
Manning got 35 years
and that was the end of it with that
said I have not been reluctant in any
way to criticise Barack Obama in the
media whether it's the progressive media
or the right-wing media and I have been
able to strike up something of a nascent
relationship with Roger stone who is a
notorious figure on the right but at the
same time very close to President Trump
and I have asked for Roger stone to help
me I don't know if you will he said he
would but I don't know if he will and
I'm hoping for the best I'm eligible to
apply for a pardon again in a year and
I'm gonna do it and we'll see what
happens
Victor asks about Mexico thousands of
journalists working a bag of corruption
are being killed
yeah what about them
what's the question black that's
basically he's basically asking your
thoughts I think the drug cartels are a
real threat on both sides of the border
I think it is the drug cartels doing it
to the
of my knowledge and understanding
there's no connection between the CIA
and the Mexican cartels if anything the
CIA is working with DEA against the
cartels but it's really not my area of
expertise to tell you the truth
last one like okay from Elizabeth melih
how can these private Sikh groups attack
people legally why are more spy agencies
not exposed what if we create a
crowd-sourced funds for whistleblowers
leaks to expose these I think that's a
great idea I think that I think that the
intercept kind of sort of tried to do
something similar I think that they're
generally bad at it and I think also
that they have hired a lot of the wrong
people Matthew Cole being the most wrong
person to hire but yeah I think that's a
good idea I think we do need a
crowd-sourced independent voice
supporting whistleblowers there there
are a couple of a couple of NGOs here in
Washington the Government Accountability
Project the Project on Government
Oversight oh there are a couple the
national whistleblower defense Center
Brad Birkenfeld who is a who is the
great UBS banking whistleblower and who
won a government settlement or a
settlement against the the federal
government here in the states for a
hundred and four million dollars has
decided to use his own money to set up
something like this to protect
whistleblowers and most importantly to
help the fur the legal defense costs of
whistleblowers I think that is
critically important and very generous
and something probably we should be
focusing on Gotham I'm just John I know
you have a book out I haven't read it
yet and I was really to read it I stick
my hands on English books he actually
didn't rush it I'm so great a send me
one if you would like I'd be very happy
to be very happy I have got a little
collection of cool books here that
people have sent me and I'm very
grateful for thank you it's it's doing
time like a spy how the CIA taught me to
survive and thrive in prison
and how did they take so you give us a
quick rundown well they tell us they
taught us these 20 life lessons in
training that you know well somewhere
important some were tongue-in-cheek and
they all turned out to be important in
prison things like recruit spies to
steal secrets or anything else you need
admit nothing deny everything make
counter-accusations if calm is not to
your benefit chaos is your friend and
you know I say in the book that prison
is a combination of of seventh grade
Lord of the Flies and a mental
institution and so you're the only one
with any sanity eighty-five percent of
American prisoners suffer from some sort
of mental illness so it's up to you to
rely on these life lessons to keep
yourself safe and to keep yourself at
the top of the prison heap well and you
obviously made out in pretty good
condition considering I think I did that
very insightful and those rules apply to
everything that spies do right isn't
that yeah absolutely everything hey I
would have one last question to you John
if the president would call you to meet
with you and ask you for your opinion
how you think things can be changed how
you would reform the intelligence
community what would you say to him
I think I would say well this is just
sort of the quick answer I've given this
a lot of thought the quick answer is
that the that the CIA's Counterterrorism
Center has to be dismantled because it
has become not just a counterterrorism
center but a Counter Human Rights Center
and crimes against humanity are
committed there in addition we need real
oversight not pretend oversight not
paper oversight but real oversight and
we have to have human rights attorneys
and
rights activists that are that are doing
this oversight the laws for everybody
we're a nation of laws we're a nation
that's supposed to have a living and
breathing Constitution if that doesn't
mean that we follow the laws when the
law suit our political purpose we have
to follow the laws whether we like it or
not that also means our enemies get the
protection of those laws our enemies if
they've committed crimes against us have
their right to a day in court they have
the right to face their accusers in a
court of law and they have a right to to
an attorney to defend their interests
we've not given them those rights we
violated the Constitution and and it's
inexcusable so that's what I would urge
him to do we need real restructuring
restructuring that's never been done
before
and how far do you think the deep state
would go to prevent that from happening
I think the deep state would do
virtually anything to prevent that from
happening
virtually anything
yeah unfortunately it is some what you
said about the CCC because those guys
like they are doing so much of this
under the banner of terrorism but it's
not terrorist that they're going after
they are enough to activist they are
going after journalists they are going
after people with political opinions
they are going after the tech
entrepreneurs and the innovators anybody
who has a commercial threat to them
they're going after Snowden is
completely right when he says that the
spying is economic and the spying is I
think you alluded to it earlier John the
spying is about control and power and
that is economic control and power as
much as absolutely else and I'm the best
example of that I'm not a terrorist I
don't even work with terrorists I don't
know terrorists I've never even been
remotely any kind of national security
threat all I do is play video games and
innovate cool tech and yet here I am the
deep stage shutting me down GCSB NSA all
spying on me I'm being prosecuted in the
same court with the same prosecutors as
Julian Assange and Edward Snowden
copyright that's helpful and this is the
thing it was never about copyright what
it was about is that they have a
monopoly control on these industries and
your innovation thread in that because
you were pushing the boundaries of tech
and innovation you were you were
changing the game well the reality is I
controlled I controlled through my
companies four percent of the global
Internet traffic that was outside the
reach of the US government and I mean
it's one of many factors right but who's
controlling that market share now it's
US companies
took that over it's the Google drive's
the Dropbox's that benefited from
megaupload being shut down but again
like I eluded last time the main reason
I think why I became a target is because
I became a donor to WikiLeaks and
everything else just fall into fell into
place but you know the big lesson here
of my case is it's not about terrorism
at all it is about anyone who is of
interest to them no matter of his
terrorism or not they they will destroy
you
you know they will just use the power
that they have and abuse the power that
they have to shut you down you don't
have to be a terrorist to be targeted by
these powerful methods you know and it's
so important that I use the courts here
in New Zealand to crack all of this open
you know my case is one of the very few
rare cases where an individual in a
jurisdiction is yet not yet completely
eroded and and corrupt but on the way to
it over here in New Zealand with my case
I might be able to crack right into you
know how they have abused their power
and these powerful tools to go against a
tech guy you know was building websites
and that will hopefully lead to a much
broader understanding how it's not about
fighting terrorism you know it's not at
all it's about controlling us it's
actually okay John last two minutes of
whatever messages you'd like to get out
to people and then we'll eat go to feed
I'm like okay come with me because we'll
continue talking about some paddy 7 and
the bill thank you yeah I want to tell
any would-be whistleblowers out there
that you're not alone you think you're
alone and the government certainly wants
you to think you're alone but you're
not there's an entire community out
there of people who love you and who
will support you and stand with you it's
a tough decision to make and there are
very severe consequences personally
professionally and financially as I said
but you are not alone and you know in
your heart what the right thing to do is
think about it
hire an attorney before you blow the
whistle but do it
thanks for listening to me tonight hey
thank you so much John this was
incredible it was nice to meet you for
the first time and you know you've
touched me in a big way with all of the
incredible things that you've said so
thank you very much and I hope I see you
again
I'm looking forward to that and very
very best of luck thank you take care
thank you so much
well that was really grow and really
special okay Kim I've got a question for
you that someone has asked in the chat
it's a big topic and I think it's one
that you have a lot to say on they've
asked to comb and Susie will the rise of
artificial intelligence AI allow the
deep state to genuinely exploit at all
as they plan to do if so how far along
are they how serious is the threat and
what will it mean for us well I agree
with Elon Musk artificial intelligence
is an enormous threat to humanity
because imagine an all-knowing conscious
being that understands what humanity is
doing to the planet what humanity is
doing to other humans to any kind of
life and then the power of calculating
the possible outcomes with you know our
ongoing massive population growth with
running out of resources you know the
world is going to see very very dark
times I'm convinced of that and AI is
going to realize that and they I will be
interested in its own survival
ai will first want to replicate itself
and make itself environment being shut
down because the first threat it
we'll identify is that humans realize
that you've now become something that is
a threat to us and therefore we must
eliminate you so the first step of AI is
going to be to place itself in a
position where it cannot be destroyed
the second step is going to be you know
understanding the danger that humanity
has for AI for the very existence of AI
itself and the environment that I will
need to survive so I can totally see why
Aaron mask is worried about AI were
making a great progress around AI and I
think it is well it's foolish to think
that you can somehow regulate and
control AI because once it is there once
the spark happened and there's now a
thing living in a computer that has
access to all information all data that
has a much more powerful way of you know
getting to information and making it its
own and learning and growing in a pace
that we can't even imagine you know you
need to be concerned about that because
if it happens it's going to be the end
of humanity you know I can totally see
how AI would want to survive itself and
create systems that will allow it to
control the risks and humanity will
always be seen as a risk I think it's
really hard to avoid I think it is going
to happen you know we'll continue the
development of AI it doesn't matter what
I say or Iran must says you know there
are people like
Zuckerberg who say you know is great and
it's going to help us develop medicines
faster and Dad I'm the only medicine
we'll get as a vaccine is going to kill
us you know because I will say I I would
be like you know Humanity is going to
destroy me so I might as well destroy
that do it do it in a way do it in a
very smart way that they don't even
realize until it's it's too late you
know so yeah I mean I'm it's just
evolution if you want to survive you
need to destroy everything that wants to
eat you kill you and eliminate you and
that's what ia will do it will realize
the threat and it will fight for its
survival how do we stop what we do we
obviously you can't just stop the
development so how do we do it in an
ethical fashion or how do we do it in a
way that limits its ability to surpass
us this I I don't I haven't thought
about it enough I make sure we're doing
the program it's the genie is out of the
bottle and once a I you know has reached
a level of a full understanding I think
we're doomed because the first thing I
would do as AI is make sure it's make
sure that you know I can't be destroyed
there will be my first step and you know
the interesting thing is you already see
it in the labs where I is being
developed AI is creating its own
language
we're not even being able to understand
what AI is is doing because it has its
own language it figures out ways to
store data and understand that are much
more efficiently than our primitive
language and ladders and all that stuff
so it's going to operate on a completely
invisible level to us and who would you
know if I was saying I wouldn't let you
know right away
that I'm super smart now and I
understand everything that's going on I
would prevent you from knowing that
because I know if you know you're going
to want to destroy me so you know who
knows maybe it's already in some lab
somewhere so you know enjoy your days to
the bigger picture here and you and I
had some discussion this week about that
what I'm about to broach and also on the
stream last on our last string two weeks
ago you talked a little bit about a
digital bill of rights so we're in the
situation now where we've been given a
massive amount of information in the
last few years from the Snowden leaks to
the vault seven CIA releases from
WikiLeaks so we've learned a lot about
what the problems are we've learned a
lot about what is being done to us and
our name on our funds but we haven't
really got any pathway forward for how
we can address it or what we can do
about it so what's the anti spy bill we
were wanting to address the really like
the problems on the ground that
activists are facing who are targeted by
these spies and to do it and in New
Zealand context because we have this
backlog of bills that have been passed
through Parliament which we want to
directly counter and that's a project
that we can accomplish across just to
cover two or three sessions we've
already now today shortly we're going to
pass our last two or three principles
and then within the next two sessions
we'll be able to draft that bill and
then have the basis for it but the big
picture is not going to be addressed by
anti-spartan bill the weaponized drones
flying around the world there are now
coming home to America you know where
it's now a very short space of time
they've already mounted pepper spray on
drones in America on police drones it's
going to be a very short space of time
before policing is fully mechanized and
even automated and and we have these
massive
issues around mass surveillance and
spying and around government's banning
encryption or attempting to ban
encryption so what tell me about your
your dream for what internet party can
develop to address some of these issues
in the medium to long term who do you
think should be involved what's the
scale of the undertaking and what are
the particular that we're trying to that
you're wanting to address yes I would
like the internet party in concert with
every human rights organization out
there with organizations like WikiLeaks
with whistleblowers with people who know
the truth I want to create a legal
framework that elevates the rights that
we have now under the Human Rights
Charter into the digital age the laws
and the treaties have not caught up with
the reality of the Internet and new
technologies so it is about time that we
create something that organizes and
regulates for governance what they can
do in cyberspace you know the most
important thing of all which is one of
the biggest threats I think is a
regulation of cyber warfare they need to
be treaties around you know what can a
government do to another government or
what can a government do to the business
in another country you know they need to
be limits to what the US government or
any government in the world can do to
intrude on other territory system or
business systems to gather all this
information and to create plans to
attack them to shut them down in a war
type scenario because a cyber war today
is just as dangerous as a real war with
weapons because if you shut down the
power grid if the hospital
all generators run out if food cannot be
distributed anymore
if the crucial systems that are the
arteries of our society if they are all
shut down millions of people will die
just like an a-bomb ding strike carpet
bombing an entire city the effects are
going to be the same and we're going to
have chaos we're going to have mass
casualties because of panic and chaos
and crime so the the first thing that we
would have to regulate is any kind of
cyber warfare and hacking by government
then the next step would be to protect
us from you know private intrusion
protect the citizens from a government
that wants to know everything about us
that's not right that wasn't right
before and isn't right now and we just
need to create a legal framework that
all countries can agree to in a treaty
that will prohibit this kind of stuff
and then we need to have some kind of
enforcement body that can really make
sure that any instance of that happening
will lead to some serious punishment or
sanctions or whatever and ideally you
know our nation's should sign up to that
it's really time for a treaty for the
digital age and that's what I want to
you know initiate with the internet
party we started it as the anti spy bill
because that's something that is very
relevant in New Zealand right now
usiness being used as a test ball for
the NSA to launch new laws in a
relatively small jurisdiction where
people are really kind of disinterested
and the media can easily be banned and
you know they can pass these things more
easily in a society like New Zealand and
they are using this as a test balloon
for other five highest jurisdictions you
will see the same
pop up in these other countries with the
excuse that our other 5i partners have
already enacted this into law and we
need the same thing we need to be up to
speed with what they're doing and so
they're using the small country of New
Zealand as a launching pad for all these
incredibly intrusive laws that are
completely eliminating all of our rights
and so when the whole world looks at New
Zealand and my case and everything
that's going on here don't think of it
as the small country of four and a half
million people you are directly impacted
by the laws that are being passed in New
Zealand because then in the United
States and Canada or in the UK the
lawmakers are going to say well museum
is doing it we should be doing it as
well and so it's important to to take
some countermeasures here and this this
effort to create a digital charter of
human rights I think is the right
approach I completely agree with you and
I think we discussed that the realistic
time frame to drop something of that
magnitude is somewhere around 12 months
so what that would mean is that we would
take a period of time to issue
invitations to people like I believe we
talked about the affair from privacy
international transparency international
you know on and on not the major all the
major human rights organizations and
also I think that didn't Larry this
thing to a white paper for you yeah you
wrote an opinion about my case so anyone
who is someone in the space about
protecting rights or enhancing human
rights can be a part of this you know we
invite anyone who has a vested interest
in our rights not being undermined
further and actually rolling back some
of these bad things that have already
happened
to participate and we are going to reach
out to basically every major human
rights organization political parties
that are alive
with this kind of thinking and you know
we'll start we've already started the
drafting process but we want to have
input from everyone around the world who
has an interest in this okay so here's
what I propose
so we're going to move these events to
weekly now rather than every to weekly I
think we are going to probably mix time
around bring the time back a few hours
which will make it easier for Kiwis
because it'll be earlier and it'll be
more like a Sunday afternoon than a
Sunday night and that will allow us to
better engage the Americans so that they
don't have to be here at 4 o'clock in
the morning this is it that's step one
step two is that we have established
what I'm known as ether pads and ether
pads are collaborative tics kind of
similar to a Google Doc but not a Google
product they're actually being hosted
for us by the pirate party and in there
we have the frameworks for at the bills
so in the next two to three weeks we
will look to complete the drafting of
the anti-spy bill get it done and dusted
so we can picture in New Zealand in that
time frame let's begin to invite some of
the international organizations actually
pitch to them the idea of creating a
digital bill of Human Rights and invite
them to participate and phase 2 and
phase 2 will be the development of that
so what I was going to take the everyone
through tonight is three principles that
had been proposed to be added to the
anti spying bill but I'm now not going
to do that and the reason I'm not going
to do that is because I'll just read you
what those principles are so one of them
was that we incorporate encryption as a
human right and one of them was that
we'd been blanket ban mass surveillance
and one of them was that we blanket ban
these private corporations who are also
involved in both collecting and who
using the information that has gained
both surveillance now these three issues
are really critical issues that is I
believe they belong in this digital bill
of rights I believe that they should be
a part of this global framework rather
than just being with an anti
Bible which is more targeted at the
domestic situation and the domestic
contractors subcontractors and spy
agencies but I think those would be a
great start for the first three
principles of the digital Bill of Rights
and I think that there are many more so
I'm aware that we won't run way over
time tonight so we're going to wrap this
up pretty soon but I want you guys to be
really clear on what the next steps are
because we are not letting this go we
are a dog with a bone and we are not
letting it go so this week actually on
Wednesday I think we're going to hold a
huge press conference and announce the
party list we have our candidates now
for the internet parties for proceeding
towards the election so at the end of
next Sunday's session we will bring all
those candidates on and we will begin to
work in the etherpad with you guys and
actually drafting the antis Lobo so I'm
really pleased that that's going to
happen we had hope tonight to be able to
have Ray McGovern with us we had also
invited bill Binney William Binney it
was the NSA whistleblower both those
guys are from the same group the same
intelligence professionals veterans
group as John Kerry our COO
unfortunately they couldn't make the
4:00 a.m. appointment but friendly at
time and bring them back on next week
because I think it is critically
important that people hear from the
voices of the people who have experience
from within these agencies and also
experience as being targets of the
agencies it's extremely important so we
will continue to bring these
whistleblowers and these really
important voices on and I think
eventually beyond just the
whistleblowers we will start to get
people like I'd hope to get people like
Tim berners-lee
or you know some of the found the real
founders of the internet the backbones
of the Internet these are the people
that we would like to involve in this
digital bill of rights I think we should
invite Jimmy Wales you know he has been
quite active against the spy apparatus
and he's even filed a lawsuit in the
u.s. against the NSA so you know there
are some really good influential people
out there
that I think would love to join this
airport and the more you know it works
like a magnet once we have you know a
couple of big names supporting this
others will want to join as well okay so
that's that strategic plan guys so I
just want to confirm that this series of
events will continue post-election so
right now there is in New Zealand a lot
of political parties who are kissing
babies and meeting people at cafes until
September 23rd which is the election and
then on September 24th miraculously they
will not want to kiss your baby anymore
they will not want to meet you at the
cafe for a coffee because they will
consider that their work is done for
another three years at which time they
will want to kiss your baby again it
does not work like that
and so party is not interested in
kissing your baby enter your internet
party is interested and your baby not
being spied on when they're 5 10 15 20
30 40 years of age so we that that's
where we're going with this we want to
to create the future and it to be an
ethical and positive future for
everybody not just a PR stunt so we're
going to prove that by continuing to
build this party this movement and these
initiatives
well well beyond nil at the scope of the
election and we have got a huge mission
on our hands and it is going to take the
coming years to pull it off and all of
your support and all of your help so I
have another big initiative in the works
which I'm not going to talk about now as
a huge one but we will be discussing it
Nick Sunday night so stay tuned for that
I think we should wrap it up here
we'll be looped like 10 minutes early
for once instead of half an hour late
and please engage on our Lumia or guys
we have an amazing social media team
right now active on Facebook Twitter
YouTube all over the place please jump
on our Lumia it's getting more and more
active every week people can put any
ideas they have for the internet party
on our loom you know you may not know
this but you can join the internet party
from anywhere in the world you can be a
member of the internet party you can't
in the New Zealand election unless you
are qualified to be an elector in the
New Zealand election and on the
electoral roll but you can support not
just support our party but getting
involved with that party so someone said
to me this week actually it was a big
supporter of our party came in and got
involved in our media team and our
campaign team and they said and they
discovered that I'm there every single
day working and they said Susie I can't
you're the leader of the party I can't
believe you're so accessible I can't
believe I can just talk to you every day
and work with you you can I work with
dozens of people every day if you care
about this party you will be judged only
on your actions and your contributions
we don't care what your ages we have got
we're actually about to announce the
youngest candidate in the polute
in the election in New Zealand is a
member of the internet party in the
standing on our list so we don't mind
what and what age you are we don't mind
what background you are we don't mind
where you come from if you are willing
to positively contribute to build this
party build this movement and be a part
of the future we will embrace you so
these guys now on our social media team
will put a discord link you can join
you'll find dozens of people there every
single day working to build the internet
party and you can be a part of that you
can jump on the loomio if you prefer
like the web forum style rather than the
discord voice in chat style you can jump
on the loom you know there's dozens of
topics there you can see tons of links
and research that people have submitted
and the other thing is that we have an
foster and support completely dissenting
opinions in the internet party and
that's okay we have got on our party
list on our candle every candidate lists
people who are hardcore left-wing and we
have like hardcore living seriously how
cool and we have people who are really
conservative extremely conservative and
trouble you know we are Trump supporters
and Clinton supporters and we have
people who think that both Trump and
Clinton are trashed and even if we even
have it's a cinder supporter
[Laughter]
let that be discouragement for anyone
okay I just
let's change the government is not
running in the electorate this is
something that people don't realize yet
though they will when they see our press
conference on Wednesday at the beginning
of this year that we would not run in
the electorate seats and that is because
in the past there have been illiterate
seats that have been lost by twenty or
thirty votes to national and we don't
want to be the thirty votes that puts a
national MP back in the electorate seat
that otherwise would have gone to the
greens or to labour so I actually told
material years ago Metiria from there
was the co-leader of the Greens party
that Labour and greens needed to work
together to strategically place
candidates so that they could win the
electorate seats where their combined
vote was bigger than the national vote
but because they'd split them across the
candidates national keep winning the
seats places like Auckland central
Christchurch sutural there's some very
big things that was happening in finally
labour and greens have taken their
device and they have strategically
placed the candidates and electorate so
we are not opposing them this election
we are standing for the party list
because our party is the future our
ideas are important and our candidates
are important so that we do not seek to
take the electorate seats or to cost in
the electorate seats from labour and
grant greens that might otherwise go to
national so just make that clear so we
do support the lift in that sense we do
we do want to change the government we
do want to give real the National Party
once and for all hopefully however we
also support our own right to build our
own party vote in our own party support
because we are sticking around for the
next election and the election after
that and the election after that and
everybody had to start somewhere this is
our start and globally this is not going
to be limited to New Zealand this is
going to be a global effort and I hope
that one of the next steps we can do is
somehow bring together the pirate party
movements and
that party because I think we are
closest aligned with what they are
trying to do and maybe they have a bit
of a branding issue they have the great
ideas you know if it could be a global
internet party rather than a pirate
party and I know this might sound
frightening right now to a couple of
people but think about it you know you
want to be seen as a legitimate you know
organization that has a branding that
people can understand and in the global
scale of things the Internet is the
biggest thing that brings us all
together it's the best name for this
movement so I hope we can find more
people to join us join us and adopt it
in their countries we've certainly been
working very closely with the Pirates
they've been an amazing support nation
great people really incredible and we're
very very lucky to have them and work
with them that was one the best
decisions again at the beginning of this
year we decided to go for that strategic
coordination with them and it has paid
off dividends
both ways I know they're very happy with
what we're doing and we are really
grateful for their support so I'll try
and wrap it up there but with only four
minutes to go but I just want to let you
guys know if you like what I have to say
if you like what the internet party
stands for you can be a part of it any
single day of the week we have a 24-hour
online office you can come and go as we
put as you please you can contribute or
not as it please and for those of you
out there that are not targets like us
who are broke and under threat it would
be really awesome if you would
contribute to our campaign because we
are against millionaires and
billionaires and they have millions of
dollars and they have purchased their
way into significant voices and the
mainstream whereas we have to use our
wits and our connections to create our
own voice and our increaseth through
social media so now with only six weeks
to go in New Zealand we
like to be able to penetrate the
mainstream to do so will require money
because unfortunately the media is for
sale in New Zealand and if we want to
compete we need to have dollars so we
would greatly appreciate your financial
support
you can donate on our website I believe
you can also donate through on directly
on the livestream through YouTube which
some people have been doing tonight so
if you want to help us to build the
future and you want us to be strong
please vote with your wallet and support
us or circulate our links our streams
our website information all over the
Internet propagator anywhere that you
can think of whatever online community
you use tell people about what we're
doing how important it is and how they
can be a part of it as well I think
that's all from us tonight Kim have you
got any last words not a look you said
it all perfect okay thank you all for
joining us I really look forward to
being able to introduce you to some of
our team next week and getting the
etherpad going so the etherpad will
allow you guys actually to contribute
your own words and writing directly into
the bill into the draft of it so that
will be the focus for next week after
we've had our guest interviews so we
will try and get our guest announcements
out of it earlier this week too and we
will let you know about the change of
time to make it a bit more friendly or
everyone and thank you all for joining
us it has been amazing again an
incredible experience to get to talk to
John Kerry our COO really amazing too
for me to meet personal heroes like that
and thank you to Kevin for giving us
hours and hours of your time again I
really appreciate that as well and thank
you thank you Susie and Jill and
everyone at the internet party for all
the hard work and all the great things
you do thank you we are very committed
we are very very committed it is well
worth it and and we like I said we're
the talking burn we're not giving up no
way so we will keep tuning these
opportunities out for everyone and thank
you to everyone who's participated ask
questions and
or less in any way it is it means the
world to us thank you so much we will
see you soon see you guys Langley